<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:itunes="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd" xmlns:itunesu="http://www.itunesu.com/feed" version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title> Real Estate Podcast with John Erik Fraker, JD</title>
    <link>http://localhost:4000</link>
    <atom10:link xmlns:atom10="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" href="http://localhost:4000"/>
    <description>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from  - your professional  Real Estate Agents.</description>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>John Erik Fraker, JD</managingEditor>
    <lastBuildDate>2019-02-15 15:12:43 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <media:copyright>John Erik Fraker, JD</media:copyright>
    <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <media:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</media:keywords>
    <media:category scheme="http://www.itunes.com/dtds/podcast-1.0.dtd">Education</media:category>
    <itunes:owner>
      <itunes:email>johnfraker@kw.com</itunes:email>
      <itunes:name>John Erik Fraker, JD</itunes:name>
    </itunes:owner>
    <itunes:author>John Erik Fraker, JD</itunes:author>
    <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
    <itunes:image href="http://localhost:4000/img/podcast.jpg"/>
    <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
    <itunes:subtitle>Learn all the tips, tricks and more for buyers and sellers in the  Area Real Estate Market</itunes:subtitle>
    <itunes:summary>If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from  - your professional  Real Estate Agents.</itunes:summary>
      <itunes:category text="Education"/>
    
      <item>
        <title>The One Mistake That Could Cost You a Fortune</title>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/the-one-mistake-that-could-cost-you-a-fortune.html</link>
        
          <category>Home Buyer Tips</category>
        
        <author>John Erik Fraker, JD</author>
        <pubDate>2019-02-08 15:44:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <guid>https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/John+Fraker/The+One+Mistake+That+Could+Cost+You+a+Fortune.mp4</guid>
        <description>

I’ve seen husbands and wives make one frequent mistake that ends up costing them hundreds of thousands of dollars on the sale of their home. That mistake is holding title as joint tenants rather than as community property.

Why is this a problem? Well, for capital gains purposes, if a husband and wife own a home as a community property and one spouse dies, it will eliminate all of your capital gains taxes. If you own the home as joint tenants, however, you’re only going to eliminate half of your capital gains exposure.

Let me give you an example. I worked with a family for many years and the parents were in their 80s. They bought their first house in the 1960s for about $20,000. Today, it’s worth more than $2 million. A few years ago, the husband passed away and the family came to me. We then found out that they were holding the property as joint tenants. That eliminated only half of their capital gains. That’s a potential six-figure tax bill to deal with. If they would have owned the property as community property, it would have eliminated that entire bill.

“Holding title as a community property can eliminate all capital gains taxes at the death of the first spouse.”

They still wanted to sell the home to get the money for their mother’s health care. Because the property was held in joint tenancy, however, they were facing a tax bill of several hundred thousand dollars! All because the deed was in joint tenancy, not community property.

Obviously, I can’t give you legal advice. However, if you’d like to take a look at your deed to see how your property is titled, don’t hesitate to give me a call or send me an email. I can also refer you to an attorney or CPA in your area who can help you decide what’s right for your family.

I look forward to hearing from you soon.
</description>
        <enclosure url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/John+Fraker/The+One+Mistake+That+Could+Cost+You+a+Fortune.mp4" length="" type="video/mp4"/>
        <media:thumbnail url="http://localhost:4000" height="72" width="72"/>
        <media:content url="https://s3.amazonaws.com/vyralmarketing/John+Fraker/The+One+Mistake+That+Could+Cost+You+a+Fortune.mp4" type="video/mp4"/>
        <itunes:explicit>no</itunes:explicit>
        <itunes:subtitle>There’s one mistake that can cost homeowners hundreds of thousands of dollars on the sale of their property. Here’s what it is.</itunes:subtitle>
        <itunes:author>John Erik Fraker, JD</itunes:author>
        <itunes:summary>There’s one mistake that can cost homeowners hundreds of thousands of dollars on the sale of their property. Here’s what it is.</itunes:summary>
        <itunes:keywords>Real Estate for sale, Real Estate agents, top real estate agents, local real estate agents, find a real estate agent, houses for sale in , home selling tips, home for sale, home buying, home buying process, property finder, property search, property, real estate market, estate agent, realestate, real estate listings, buying a house, homes for sale, mls, home buyer</itunes:keywords>
      </item>
      
    <copyright>John Erik Fraker, JD</copyright>
    <media:credit role="author">John Erik Fraker, JD</media:credit>
    <media:rating>nonadult</media:rating>
    <media:description type="plain">If you are looking to buy or sell a home, get all the information and the latest updates, tips, and tricks from  - your professional  Real Estate Agents.</media:description>
  </channel>
</rss>
